[神秘的音乐播放]
[mysterious music playing]
(流潺潺)
[stream gurgling]
[播放歌剧音乐]
[operatic music playing]
[电话那边的人]Jakub。你要加入这个广播吗?
[man over comms] Jakub. Are you joining this broadcast?
我们得把你接上。
We need to patch you in.
坚持下去。
Hang on.
(点击切换)
[switch clicks]
[神秘的音乐加强]
[mysterious music intensifies]
(金属摇摇欲坠)
[metallic creaking]
(呼呼)
[whirring]
来吧。
Come on.
(喘着粗气)
[breathing heavily]
(呼呼加剧)
[whirring intensifies]
(转动停止)
[whirring stops]
(机开始)
[machine starts]
[电气嗡嗡声和蜂鸣声]
[electrical buzzing and beeping]
[Jakub]彼得。
[Jakub] Peter.
(彼得越过扬声器)现在接通你的电话。
[Peter over speakers] Patching you in now.
(鼓掌)
[people applauding]
我代表欧洲太空计划和捷克人民，
On behalf of the Euro Space Program and the Czech people,
你独自旅行的第189天，
欢迎回来，指挥官Procházka。
welcome back, Commander Procházka.
Tuma专员。来自木星外围的你好。
Commissioner Tuma. Hello from the outskirts of Jupiter.
我很高兴能在这里和你交谈。
I'm very excited to be talking to you from here.
再次见到你真是太好了。你气色不错。
It's so great to see you again. You look well.
看来漫长的等待即将结束。
It seems like the long wait is coming to an end.
(轻声地笑)是的，没错。
[chuckles softly] Yes, that is correct.
这次旅行的原因就在我面前。
The reason for this journey is right in front of me.
我确信我传回来的照片并不能很好地展现它。
I'm sure the images I've sent back doesn't do it justice.
但乔普拉云比你想象的更令人惊讶。
But the Chopra Cloud is more astonishing than what you could ever imagine.
我希望你们都能像我一样看待它。
I wish you could all see it the way I do.
这种现象在过去的四年里一直困扰着我们的天空，
[Tuma] This phenomenon has haunted our skies for the past four years,
现在你的照片吸引了全世界。
and now your images have captivated the world.
真正壮观。
Truly spectacular.
(温柔的笑)
[chuckles softly]
不到一个星期，
Well, in less than a week,
我会收集并分析构成云层的粒子。
I will collect and analyze the particles that make up the cloud.
我们仍然不知道它们是什么，也不知道它们来自哪里。
We still don't know what they are or where they come from.
但当我进入乔普拉云时，
But as I enter the Chopra Cloud,
我可能会解开宇宙的一些谜团。
I might just unravel some mysteries of the universe.
指挥官，你介意回答几个问题吗
Commander, would you mind taking a few questions
从世界人民那里?
from the people of the world?
我会尽力的。
I'll do my best.
[女孩]你好，我叫安娜。
[girl] Hello, my name is Anna.
我上六年级了。
I'm in sixth grade.
我读到你是世界上最孤独的人。
And I read that you're the loneliest man in the world.
(温柔的笑)
[chuckles softly]
我想安娜的意思是指挥官
I think what Anna here is saying is that the commander
是历史上离任何人都最远的。
is the farthest away from anyone in history.
你是这个意思吗?
Is that what you mean?
这么远的地方会让你难过吗?
Does it make you sad to be so far away?
我在5亿公里之外。
Well, I am some 500 million kilometers away.
是的，这是一个单独的任务，但我知道我很快就会回来的。
And yes, this is a solo mission, but I know I'll be coming back soon.
我已经接近预定返回地球的一半了，
I'm nearing the halfway mark for my scheduled return to Earth,
我有很多工作要做
and I have so much work to do.
我可以和来自世界各地的人交谈
And I get to talk to people from all over the world
就像你和任务控制中心。
like you and Mission Control.
当然还有你的妻子，伦卡。
And your wife, Lenka, of course.
她和我可以通过CzechConnect量子网络聊天
She and I can talk over the CzechConnect Quantum
比光速还快
faster than the Speed of Light Phone,
这让我们保持联系。
which keeps us connected.
我们每天都聊天。
We talk every day.
我所做的一切都是为了家乡的每一个人，这让我非常自豪。
What I'm doing is for everyone back home, and that makes me very proud.
不，我不是世界上最孤独的人。
No, I'm not the loneliest man in the world.
谢谢你，安娜。
Thank you, Anna.
谢谢你，指挥官。
And thank you, Commander.
我们在这里休息一下，
We're going to take a short break here,
我们将在慷慨的赞助商致辞后回来。
and we'll be back after a word from our generous sponsors.
(听众鼓掌)
[audience applauding]
[欢快的音乐播放]
[upbeat music playing]
[旁白]不昏昏欲睡的古董，
[narrator] Non-drowsy Antiquease,
Jakub Procházka驻乔普拉使团的官方恶心药物。
the official nausea medication of the Jakub Procházka Mission to Chopra.
[忧郁的音乐播放]
[melancholy music playing]
你会没事的，雅各布。
[Lenka] You'll be all right, Jakub.
你不害怕独自一人。
You're not afraid to be on your own.
我很害怕，
I was afraid,
但我已经不是了。
but I'm not anymore.
(抽泣)
[sniffles]
(啜泣)我爱你。
[sobbing] I love you.
但是人是会变的。
But people change.
如果你不让他们改变，他们就会死。
And if you don't let them change, they die.
(抽泣)
[sniffles]
(哭)我必须离开你。
[cries] I have to leave you.
我很抱歉必须是现在，但是
I'm so sorry it has to be now, but--
(哔哔声)
[beeps]
(线响)
[line ringing]
(人)是吗?
[man] Yes?
Lenka问题。
Lenka problem.
(机器转动)
[machine whirring]
[呼呼声增强，停止]
[whirring intensifies, stops]
彼得，你能同意再修一次厕所吗?
Peter, would you be so kind to approve another repair to the toilet?
(叹气)让我看看能不能让工程部澄清一下。
[sighs] Let me see if I can get engineering to clear that.
你按我们建议的换了o形圈了吗?
Did you replace the O-rings like we suggested?
是的，我做了。
Yes, I did.
它还在尖叫。
And it's still screaming.
也许你和我以后可以解决这个问题。
Maybe you and I can troubleshoot it later.
但命令是要优先处理坏掉的摄像头，所以…
But the orders are that the broken cameras take priority over the toilet, so…
你昨晚什么时候吃的安眠药?
When did you take your sleep drops last night?
8:30。为什么?
你看起来不太好。你睡觉了吗?
You don't look so good. Did you sleep?
我试过了。
I tried.
但也许我看起来像坨屎
But just maybe I look like shit
因为厕所总是搅乱我的夜晚。
because the toilet keeps fucking up my nights.
[彼得]好的，我明白了。
[Peter] Okay, I hear you.
但是尽量找时间打个盹。你需要休息。
But try to find time for a nap. You need rest.
你们有Lenka的消息吗?
[Jakub] Have you guys heard from Lenka?
不。为什么?
No. Why?
[忧郁的音乐播放]
[melancholy music playing]
(跑步机转动)
[treadmill whirring]
(喘着粗气)
[breathing heavily]
(机器进入)
[machine whooshes]
(Lenka对着笔记本电脑)我知道你能感觉到寂静。
[Lenka over laptop] I know you can feel the silence.
(抽泣)
[sniffles]
(叹气)天哪，天哪。
[sighs] Oh my, oh my.
[Lenka]我们都在CzechConnect上…
[Lenka] We're both on the CzechConnect and…
只有寂静。
there's just silence.
那么重点是什么呢?
So what's the point?
他承受着巨大的压力。他没有睡觉。
He is under tremendous pressure. He isn't sleeping.
他听不懂这个信息。
He's not getting this message.
-我们在隐瞒?——(Tuma)嗯。
-We're holding it back? -[Tuma] Hm.
(叹气)他已经开始担心没有她的消息了。
[sighs] He's already concerned he hasn't heard from her.
他听不懂这个信息。
He's not getting this message.
我去和她谈谈。
I'll go talk to her.
我会想办法告诉他的。
I'll think of something to tell him.
(电话响了)
[phone ringing]
(手机嘀嘀声)
[phone beeps]
[自动语音]Lenka不接电话。如果你想留言的话
[automated voice] Lenka is not answering. If you'd like to leave a message--
CzechConnect让你保持联系。
CzechConnect keeps you connected.
[CzechConnect主题音乐播放]
[CzechConnect theme music plays]
[播放忧郁的音乐]
[somber music playing]
(音乐加剧)
[music intensifies]
(机器转动)
[machine whirring]
(Jakub低声呻吟)
[Jakub whimpers]
(Jakub呻吟)
[Jakub groans]
[呻吟和裤子]
[groans and pants]
(呼呼继续)
[whirring continues]
(转动停止)
[whirring stops]
(喘着粗气)
[breathing heavily]
(喘气)
[gasping]
(呼吸颤抖)
[breath trembling]
哦……
Oh…
啊!
Ah!
怎么啦？
What?
(的)
[grunting]
[怪异的音乐播放]
[eerie music playing]
(窒息)
[choking]
(尖叫)
[screaming]
(叹息)
[groans]
(跑步机转动)
[treadmill whirring]
[彼得]你很清楚
[Peter] You are clear
用于Chopra样品采集模拟。
for the Chopra Sample Collection Simulation.
确认方案beta -3。
Confirming scenario beta 3-3.
[Jakub]样本采集模拟确认。
[Jakub] Sample collection simulation confirmed.
彼得，你在看书吗?
Peter, are you reading?
彼得:还是没有D号相机?
[Peter] Still no Camera D?
是的。电好。相机死了。同样的故事。
Yes. Electrical fine. Camera dead. Same story.
[彼得]那是船上一半的摄像机失灵了。
[Peter] That's half the ship's cameras malfunctioning.
我不明白发生了什么。
I don't understand what's happening.
我会再提交一份报告。(叹息)
I'll file another report. [sighs]
我相信那会很有效的。
I'm sure that'll be very effective.
[忧郁的音乐播放]
[melancholy music playing]
[Jakub]有人能去我家吗?
[Jakub] Can someone go to my home?
(彼得)为什么?
[Peter] Why?
(雅库布)还是没有她的消息。
[Jakub] Still haven't heard from her.
[彼得]好的，我们会找到她的。别担心。
[Peter] Okay, we'll find her. Don't worry.
(电话嘟嘟)
[phone beeping]
[自动语音]Lenka不接电话。如果你想留言的话
[automated voice] Lenka is not answering. If you'd like to leave a message--
(静态嗡嗡声)
[static buzzing]
[怪异的音乐播放]
[eerie music playing]
Lenka吗?
Lenka?
喂?
Hello?
[通过CzechConnect的人]你好。
[man over CzechConnect] Hello.
你是谁?
Who is this?
这是谁?
Who do I have here?
我能帮你吗?
[man] Can I help you?
这到底是谁?
Who the hell is this?
喂?
Hello?
我很抱歉。
[man] My apologies.
彼得，你在听吗?
Peter, are you on?
(彼得)是的。
[Peter] Yes.
有干扰。
I'm getting interference.
[彼得]这太奇怪了。
[Peter] That's very strange.
会不会有人黑了CzechConnect?
Could someone have hacked the CzechConnect?
[彼得]嗯，不太可能。我们的系统很安全。
[Peter] Mmm, not likely. Our system is secure.
如果有干扰，那是通过无线电，但是…
If there's interference, it's over the radio, but…
是韩语吗?
Was it Korean?
[Jakub]为什么是韩语?
[Jakub] Why would it be Korean?
(彼得叹了口气)有迹象表明韩国人正在逼近。
[Peter sighs] There are indications the South Koreans are closing in.
不是韩语。
It's not Korean.
可能有人把频道开着了。
Someone probably just left the channel open here.
你有什么建议?
And what do you suggest?
(彼得叹了口气)我会调查的。
[Peter sighs] I'll look into it.
你还好吗?一切都还好吗?
You doing okay? Is everything all right?
是的，彼得，一切都很好。
Yes, Peter, everything is very good.
彼得:听着，我们刚刚了解到
[Peter] So listen, we've just learned
伦卡要去看她妈妈了
that Lenka's on her way to visit her mother.
她过几天就会回来。
She'll be back in a couple of days.
(Jakub)是吗?让她给我打电话。
[Jakub] Yeah? Get her to call me.
(对象砰砰声)
[object thuds]
(砰砰声)
[thuds]
(门)
[door opens]
[播放悬疑音乐]
[suspenseful music playing]
(机器转动)
[machine whirring]
(叹息)
[sighs]
(喘息)
[gasps]
搞什么鬼?
What the fuck?
控制中心，你脑袋里有秘密摄像头吗?
Control, do you have a secret camera in the head?
——(彼得)为什么?你做了什么?
-[Peter] Why? -You do?
(彼得)是的。这是一个安全问题。
[Peter] Yeah. Well, it's a safety issue.
现在把它拉上来。
Pull it up right now.
[彼得]但是它出去了。它是第一批被淘汰的。
[Peter] But it's out. It was one of the first ones to go out.
你在开玩笑吧。
You gotta be kidding me.
Jakub，发生什么事了?喂?
[Peter] Jakub, what's going on? Hello?
雅各布，你为什么不回应?
Jakub, why aren't you responding?
[蜘蛛]我被你电视里沉思的声音催眠了。
[spider] I was lulled by the meditative sounds of your tube.
我没想吓你，瘦骨嶙峋的人。
I did not intend to frighten you, skinny human.
-[彼得]Jakub，怎么了?-[蜘蛛]不要害怕。
-[Peter] Jakub, what's going on? -[spider] Do not be afraid.
(彼得)喂?
[Peter] Hello?
[Jakub]我要疯了。
[Jakub] I'm losing my mind.
[彼得]你为什么在气闸里?
[Peter] Why are you in the airlock?
我们必须清除飞船的污染!
[Jakub] We have to decontaminate the ship!
(彼得)什么?为什么?
[Peter] What? Why?
以防万一。以防船上有污染物。
As a precaution. In case we have any onboard contaminants.
[彼得]嗯，我们在下面的传感器上没有看到任何东西。
[Peter] Well, we're not seeing anything on our sensors down here.
[Jakub]我得到了一些非常奇怪的读数，
[Jakub] I have been getting some very strange readings,
我需要在任务进入关键阶段前确定
and I need to be certain before the critical stage of the mission.
我在穿衣服。
I'm suiting up.
好吧，你是指挥官。
All right, you're the commander.
给我点时间清理一下。
Give me a minute to clear this.
(点击切换)
[switch clicks]
彼得，我需要消息。
[Jakub] Peter, I need word.
我……(叹气)……只是勉强得到了确认。
I… [sighs] …just got a reluctant confirmation.
我收到了一些公司的赞助
I'm hearing from corporate sponsorships
他们想让你先说口号。
that they want you to say the slogan first.
(Jakub)什么?
[Jakub] What?
[彼得]在你部署去污剂之前。
[Peter] Before you deploy the decontaminant.
Bomba的口号。
The Bomba slogan.
两个,三个……
Two, three…
Bomba的有效性为99.999%
Bomba is 99.999% effective
杀死所有空气中的微生物元素。
in killing any and all airborne microbial elements.
即使在太空中，也不要让细菌毁了你的一天。
Even in space, don't let germs ruin your day.
Bomba,走!
Bomba, away!
(咂咂舌头)好吧。很好。可以走了。
[clicks tongue] All right. Very good. Clear to go.
(哔哔声)
[beeps]
(机器发出嘶嘶声)
[machine hissing]
[播放忧郁的音乐]
[somber music playing]
我去哪里你就去哪里
[Lenka] You go where I go,
你去哪儿我就去哪儿
and I go where you go.
宇航员?
Right, Spaceman?
(彼得)Jakub吗?
[Peter] Jakub?
怎么啦？
What?
[彼得]你没事吧?
[Peter] Are you okay?
这是怎么呢？
What's going on?
[Jakub]有点不对劲。
[Jakub] Something's not right.
[彼得]怎么了?
[Peter] What's not right?
Jakub吗?
Jakub?
[雅各]我很好。
[Jakub] I'm fine.
我要和兰卡谈谈。
I need to talk to Lenka.
[彼得]你得跟我谈谈。
[Peter] You need to talk to me.
我知道，我知道。
I know, I know.
[彼得]你的幸福是我的责任。
[Peter] Your well-being is my responsibility.
你得对我坦白。
You need to be transparent with me.
我知道，我也是。
I know, and I am.
(彼得叹了口气)好吧。
[Peter sighs] Okay.
几分钟后大气层就会恢复正常。
The atmosphere should be back to normal in a couple of minutes.
你的传感器有什么反应?
What are your sensors saying?
(Jakub)嗯。
[Jakub] Hm.
[彼得]看到什么不寻常的事了吗?
[Peter] See anything unusual?
[Jakub]现在不行。
[Jakub] Not right now.
[播放悬疑音乐]
[suspenseful music playing]
[彼得]如果你需要找人谈谈，我们可以请Kuřák医生来。
[Peter] We can have Dr. Kuřák come in if you need someone to talk to.
我不需要心理医生。我…我很好。
I don't need a psychiatrist. I'm… I'm fine.
我不希望你的精神状况影响到这次任务。
I don't want your mental well-being to call this mission into question.
同意了。
Agreed.
你不用担心我。
You don't need to worry about me.
[彼得]这就是我的工作。
[Peter] That is what my job is.
单独相处六个月，你开始想太多了。
Six months apart in isolation, you start thinking too much.
[Jakub]是的，我需要回到那里，彼得。
[Jakub] Yeah, I need to get back out there, Peter.
(彼得)好。
[Peter] Okay.
[蜘蛛]我能感觉到你的恐惧。
[spider] I sense your fear.
但我并不想伤害你。
But I do not mean you any harm.
你不必担心。
You needn't worry.
在与地球清洁剂的接触中，我没有感到任何痛苦。
I experienced no pain in my encounter with Earth's cleaning agents.
只有……
Only…
(打喷嚏)
[sneezes]
(呼吸颤抖)
[breath trembling]
[蜘蛛]对不起。
[spider] My apologies.
你不需要你的保护壳。
You do not need your protective shell.
我既不会消耗你，也不会污染你。
I will neither consume nor contaminate you.
啊。你想知道我是否真实。
Ah. You wish to know if I am real.
是吗?
Are you?
[蜘蛛]我和你一样真实。
[spider] I am as real as you are.
[Jakub]你不可能。
[Jakub] You can't be.
[彼得]那是什么，雅各布?
[Peter] What was that, Jakub?
不不不不不不。
No, no, no, no, no.
彼得，没什么。
Peter, it's nothing.
[蜘蛛]我希望你不要那样做。
[spider] I would prefer you do not do that.
这不是我们部落的习惯。
It is not customary for my tribe.
身体不能被侵犯。
The body must not be violated.
(宇航服嘘声)
[spacesuit hisses]
(呼吸颤抖)
[breath trembling]
你为什么在这里?
Why are you here?
[蜘蛛]我和你一样，是个探险家。
[spider] I am like you, an explorer.
但你为什么在这艘船上?
But why are you on this vessel?
[蜘蛛]我正在你们太阳系的边缘旅行
[spider] I was traveling to the edges of your solar system
当我感受到人类的吸引力时
when I felt the pull of humans.
我从轨道上观测了你们的地球，研究了你们的历史，
I surveyed your Earth from orbit, studied your history,
学习你们的语言。
learned your languages.
然而在获得了你的知识之后，
Yet having accessed your knowledge,
我还是不明白。
I still did not understand.
就在那时我遇到了你的船。
That is when I encountered your ship.
你的孤独引起了我的兴趣。
Your loneliness intrigued me.
我本来打算研究你一两天，但后来我想知道更多。
I intended to study you a day or two, but then I wished to know more.
你强迫我。
You compelled me.
我开始明白我也许能帮上忙。
I've come to understand that I might be of help.
我必须……(颤抖地呼吸)
I have to… [breathes shakily]
(蜘蛛)人吗?
[spider] Human?
瘦小的人吗?
Skinny human?
我不打扰你了。
I will leave you alone.
我这是怎么了?
[Jakub] What's happening to me?
[神秘音乐演奏]
[mystical music playing]
[Lenka]这将是我们的家，Jakub。
[Lenka] This is going to be our home, Jakub.
(喘息)
[gasps]
[播放悬疑音乐]
[suspenseful music playing]
当你爱上一个人，你就注定要截肢
When you love someone, you're meant to amputate
把你的一部分，换成另一个人的一部分。
a piece of what is you and replace it with a piece of the other.
[蜘蛛]不要害怕。
[spider] Do not be afraid.
[Jakub]这是什么?
[Jakub] What is this?
你知道我把自己割了那么多吗
Do you get that I fucking amputated so much of myself
我都不知道自己是谁了?
I don't even know who I am anymore?
-你放弃了吗?-不管。
-What have you given up, huh? -Whatever.
你要这样对我吗?
Are you doing this to me?
(对象卡嗒卡嗒响)
[objects clattering]
我去哪儿你就去哪儿，你去哪儿我就去哪儿。宇航员?
You go where I go, and I go where you go. Right, Spaceman?
[蜘蛛]我想帮助你摆脱精神上的痛苦。
[spider] I wish to assist you in your emotional distress.
你的伴侣似乎在疏远你。
It seems your mate is pulling away.
也许我的出现能减轻你的孤独。
Perhaps my presence can lessen your solitude.
我不需要你的帮助。
I don't need your help.
但你知道。
But you do.
[忧郁的音乐播放]
[melancholy music playing]
在这个国家有一个地方是为单身的孕妇准备的。
There's a place in the country for pregnant women who are alone.
它们住在一起，吃在一起，
They live together, eat together,
在分娩和最初的几周内互相支持。
support each other through the birth and the first few weeks.
我…我不明白。
I… I don't understand.
你宁愿在森林里被陌生人包围吗?
You'd rather be surrounded by strangers in a forest?
我已经取消了在汉堡的演讲
I already canceled my lecture in Hamburg--
请站在我这边。
Be on my side, please.
我是。
I am.
我一直都是。
I always am.
但是，宝贝，现在做重大决定太疯狂了。
But, baby, this is a crazy time to make big decisions.
现在离开他真是太疯狂了。
It's a crazy time to leave him.
我知道。
I know.
我早就该这么做了。
I should have done it a long time ago.
[忧郁的音乐播放]
[melancholy music playing]
(听不清)
[inaudible]
[开门，打开]
[door unlocks, opens]
[蜘蛛]瘦瘦的人?
[spider] Skinny human?
-不!不!-[蜘蛛]我想问问你的伴侣。
-No! No! -[spider] I need to ask about your mate.
这个房间禁止入内。
This room's off limits.
(遥远的转动)
[distant whirring]
(呼呼继续)
[whirring continues]
[蜘蛛]有一张你的照片。
[spider] There is a picture of you.
你是你部落的光荣成员?
You are an honored member of your tribe?
这个房间也是禁止进入的。
This room is also off limits.
给我。
Give me those.
你有很多底线，瘦子。
You have many boundaries, skinny human.
也许他们是你孤独的原因。
Perhaps they are the cause of your loneliness.
出去。
Get out.
(叹息)
[sighs]
[蜘蛛]你有卵子吗?
[spider] Do you have any ova?
鸟类的变种。
Of the avian variety.
瘦小的人吗?
Skinny human?
你指的是鸡蛋吗?
Are you referring to eggs?
[蜘蛛]是的，我想试一试。
[spider] Yes, I wish to sample them.
你这样看待他们。
You set them in such regard.
我没有。它们不适合旅行。
I don't have any. They don't travel well.
(蜘蛛)哦。
[spider] Oh.
你想试试这个吗?
Do you want to sample this?
(蜘蛛)嗯。
[spider] Hmm.
嗯。
Mmm.
像家乡的shtoma幼虫一样浓郁柔滑。
Rich and creamy like the shtoma larvae back home.
你的家到底在哪里?
Where is home for you exactly?
[蜘蛛]丢了。
[spider] It is lost.
戈罗姆人来找我们了。
The Gorompeds came for us.
和你一样，我逃离了我的星球。
Just like you, I fled my planet.
穿过星系，穿过黑洞。
Through galaxies, through black holes.
我穿越宇宙，穿越时空，寻找慰藉。
I fled through the universe, through time, looking for solace.
但后来我找到了你。
But then I found you.
这就是你们这种人对待孤独的方式吗?
Is this how your kind treats your feelings of loneliness?
我想这是一种方式。
It's one way I suppose.
[旋翼叶片旋转]
[rotor blades whirring]
[图玛]她知道自己嫁给了谁。
[Tuma] She knew who she married.
所有这些品质都让他有能力独自在太空中度过一年
All the qualities that make him capable of spending a year alone in space
这让他…
makes him, uh…
特有的。
peculiar.
她会跟你说话吗?
[woman] Will she even talk to you?
她怀孕了，很孤独。
She's very pregnant and very alone.
当你一个人的时候，你会想。
And when you're alone, you think.
她想得太多了。
She's had too much time to think.
[蜘蛛]我们有工作要做。
[spider] We have work to do.
你有时间吗?
[Lenka] You have time for this?
我还以为你会盯着天上的云呢。
Thought you'd be staring up at your cloud.
(彼得)Jakub。
[Peter] Jakub.
Jakub。
Jakub.
怎么啦？
What?
Peter:我们发现Lenka的CzechConnect存在一些问题。
[Peter] We've identified some issues with Lenka's CzechConnect.
——(Jakub)好。——(蜘蛛)。
-[Jakub] Okay. -[spider] Come.
[Jakub]什么时候修好?
[Jakub] When is it fixed?
[彼得]我们的工程师正在处理。
[Peter] Our engineers are on it.
是吗?谢谢你！
Yeah? Thank you.
听着，彼得，我得回去了。
Look, Peter, I got to get back to it.
[彼得]你去吧。
[Peter] You do that.
[Jakub]这云……
[Jakub] This cloud…
你也觉得很美吗?
it's beautiful to you too?
它有很多智慧，瘦骨嶙峋的人。
[spider] It holds much wisdom, skinny human.
我小的时候，舌头上沾过它的颗粒。
When I was young, I caught its grains on my tongue.
它们来自太初。
They are from the Beginning.
这些粒子……
These particles…
它们来自宇宙的起源?
They are from the origin of the universe?
这就是乔普拉吗?
Is that what Chopra is?
(蜘蛛)。
[spider] Perhaps.
你当时也在场?
And you were there?
你多大了?
How old are you?
你们这种人不会死吗?
Do your kind not die?
[蜘蛛]有始必有终，瘦弱的人。
[spider] Everything that begins must end, skinny human.
甚至宇宙本身。
Even the universe itself.
它在把我们拉进去。
It's pulling us in.
里面有东西吗?
Is there something inside?
(蜘蛛)是的。
[spider] Yes.
[Jakub]这是什么?
[Jakub] What is it?
[蜘蛛]《开始》。
[spider] The Beginning.
一个开始。
The Beginning.
这是什么?
What is this?
我有个提议。
I have a proposition for you.
我去哪儿你就去哪儿。
You go where I go.
你去哪儿我就去哪儿。
And I go where you go.
交易吗?
Deal?
-是的。- - - - - -[笑]
-Yeah. -[chuckles]
-[Jakub]你要带我去哪里?-[Lenka笑]相信我!
-[Jakub] Where are you taking me? -[Lenka chuckles] Trust me!
[Jakub]好吧，你去哪儿我就去哪儿。
[Jakub] Okay, I'll go where you go.
[蜘蛛]我不明白。
[spider] I don't understand.
如果一个承诺很容易被打破，为什么还要信守它呢?
Why commit to a promise if it can readily be broken?
这样的承诺有什么目的呢?
What purpose does such a commitment serve?
这些想法是你自己产生的吗?
Are you creating these thoughts?
(蜘蛛)。
[spider] No.
这些是你的想法。
These are your thoughts.
我只是和你一起寻找它们。
I am simply finding them with you.
不,不。
No, no.
我不会允许的。
I'm not allowing that.
停下你正在做的事。
Stop what you're doing.
[蜘蛛]你为什么抗拒这种探索?
[spider] Why do you resist this exploration?
让我来帮你。
Let me help you.
我不喜欢水。
I don't love water.
我是救生员。我可以当救生员。
I'm a lifeguard. I could be a lifeguard.
我会救你的。
I will save you.
[蜘蛛]只有当你的伴侣离开时，你才会渴望她。
[spider] You long for your mate only once she leaves.
随便你。
Suit yourself.
(蜘蛛)为什么?
[spider] Why?
你们在一起时的思念在哪里?
Where was this yearning when you were together?
我不知道该怎么回答你。
I don't have any answers for you.
[蜘蛛]这与你的伦卡的冲突，
[spider] This strife with your Lenka,
它在我心中激起了某种我不认识的东西。
it stirs something in me I do not recognize.
你的回忆让我…
Your memories are making me…
沮丧?
depressed?
但是用榛子做的酱
But the spread made of hazelnut
让我的意识没那么不愉快了。
did make my realization seem less unpleasant.
也许我们得留点以后再用。
Maybe we need to save some for later then.
有没有觉得你可能会蒸发?
Ever felt like you might evaporate?
这就是我的感受。
That's how I felt.
我有希望。
And I have hope.
很快就会好起来的。
It'll get better soon.
我来收拾。我不会蒸发。
I'll get it together. I'm not going to evaporate.
只是……
It's just that…
他看不见我。
he can't see me.
不是真的。下面的世界……
Not really. The world down here…
我们只是点。(抽泣)
We're just dots. [sniffles]
你不是一个点。
You're not a dot.
[伦卡]我知道。
[Lenka] I know.
这就是我想出来的。
That's what I worked out.
我确实存在。
I do exist.
独自抚养一个孩子是很困难的。
Raising a kid alone is hard.
(小鸟喳喳叫)
[birds chirping]
[Lenka深深地叹了口气]
[Lenka sighs deeply]
你想过要怎么跟孩子说吗?
Have you thought about what you're going to tell the baby?
我会告诉我们的女儿真相。
I'll tell our daughter the truth.
当我嫁给她父亲时……
When I married her father…
我爱他。
I loved him.
我喜欢他的雄心壮志。
I loved that he was ambitious.
我错了。
I was wrong.
年轻人总是错的。
Young people are wrong all the time.
人们总是错的。
People are wrong all the time.
(Lenka叹了口气)
[Lenka sighs]
你有名字吗?
Do you have a name?
我该怎么称呼你?
What am I supposed to call you?
[蜘蛛]我从来没有名字。
[spider] I have never had a name.
你能给我一个吗?
Would it help you to give me one?
它会。
It would.
[蜘蛛]那说出我的名字。
[spider] Then name me.
你能想到一个适合我的吗?
Can you think of one that becomes me?
哈努斯呢?
How about Hanuš?
(蜘蛛)Hanuš……
[spider] Hanuš…
[Jakub]我父亲跟我说过他。
[Jakub] My father told me about him.
他在布拉格建造了天文钟。
He built the astronomical clock in Prague.
它测量恒星和行星的运动。
It measured the movements of the stars and the planets.
这是世界上绝无仅有的。
It was like nothing else in the world.
[蜘蛛]你的哈努什怎么了?
[spider] What happened to your Hanuš?
有个国王把他的眼睛戳出来了。
Some king poked his eyes out.
我想是嫉妒吧。这威胁到了他的遗产。
Jealousy, I believe. It threatened his legacy.
(蜘蛛)好奇。
[spider] Curious.
计时机呢?
And the timekeeping machine?
现在起作用了。
It works now.
但我不确定这是否是哈努斯建造的……
But I'm not sure if Hanuš built it…
或者如果别人做了……
or if someone else did…
或者哈努斯是否存在
or if Hanuš even exists.
我将被称为哈努斯。
I will be called Hanuš.
好。
Good.
Hanuš。
Hanuš.
[通过扬声器播放歌剧音乐]
[operatic music playing over speakers]
(呼呼)
[whirring]
[音乐音量增大]
[music volume increases]
(转动停止)
[whirring stops]
[哈努什]这是一部悲剧?
[Hanuš] This is a tragic opera?
是关于什么的?
What is it about?
[Jakub]我是Rusalka。
[Jakub] This is Rusalka.
爱上凡人的水仙。
A water nymph who falls in love with a mortal man.
但他们不能在一起。
But they can't be together.
哈努什:你在这对不幸的恋人身上看到了自己。
[Hanuš] You see yourself in the star-crossed lovers.
[Lenka]别害怕。
[Lenka] Don't be scared.
[Jakub]我是一名正在训练的宇航员。我从不害怕。
[Jakub] I'm a cosmonaut in training. I'm never scared.
[Lenka]你一直想当宇航员吗?
[Lenka] Did you always want to be a cosmonaut?
[Jakub]嗯，我应该养猪的。
[Jakub] Well, I was supposed to raise pigs.
(Lenka)真的吗?
[Lenka] Really?
但父亲去世后，我的梦想变得更大了。
But after my father died, my dreams got bigger.
我父亲也死了。
My father's dead too.
你要带我去哪里?
[Jakub] Where are you taking me?
[Lenka]我想你可能想看些东西。
[Lenka] I thought you might want to see something.
这是什么?
What is this?
这是一个秘密的地方。
It's a secret place.
[哈努斯]有太多的爱。
[Hanuš] There was so much love.
它去哪儿了?
Where did it go?
请不要再这样对我了。
Please stop doing this to me.
我们必须坚持下去，瘦骨嶙峋的人。
[Hanuš] We must persist, skinny human.
(尖叫)
[squeals]
(喘息)
[gasps]
(猪反常的)
[pigs squealing]
(古斯塔夫·胡萨克，捷克语)同胞们，亲爱的同志们。
[Gustav Husak, in Czech] Fellow citizens, dear comrades.
人民不再相信共产党的统治。
The people no longer trust in the rule of the Communist Party.
今天，我向你们发表讲话，以确保我们能够避免一个无法无天的国家。
Today, I speak to you to ensure we can avoid a lawless state.
我将辞去我作为捷克斯洛伐克社会主义共和国总统的职务。
I will abdicate my role as the president of the Czechoslovak Socialist Republic.
我希望我们的国家和人民民主发展成功。
I hope for a successful democratic development of our state and its people.
(机器转动)
[machine whirring]
(转动停止)
[whirring stops]
你整晚都在这儿听那个吗?
[in English] Were you just here listening to that all night?
我觉得振动很舒缓。
I find the vibrations soothing.
起初，我和你一起进入你的思想。
At first, I entered your thoughts with you.
但我觉得不舒服。
But I felt uncomfortable.
你们这种人背负着巨大的罪恶感。
Your kind carries a great deal of guilt.
你的不?
Yours doesn't?
不。我们为什么要这么做?
No. Why should we?
宇宙就是它应该有的样子。
The universe is as it should be.
我要解除你对这个房间的禁令，哈努斯。
I am removing your ban on this room, Hanuš.
为了舒缓的目的。
For soothing purposes.
(跑步机转动)
[treadmill whirring]
[哈努斯]这有什么目的?
[Hanuš] What purpose does this serve?
我每天必须做两个小时，以防止我的骨头腐烂。
I have to do this two hours a day to keep my bones from decaying.
你选择逃离你的星球，
[Hanuš] You chose to flee your planet,
但这种行为对你是有害的。
yet that act is destructive to you.
你的父亲。我可以问一下他的情况吗?
Your father. May I ask about him?
(猪反常的)
[pigs squealing]
他怎么样了?
What about him?
[哈努斯]他怎么了?
[Hanuš] What happened to him?
他因为相信真相而被杀。
He was killed for what he believed was the truth.
[哈努斯]你父亲是烈士?
[Hanuš] Your father was a martyr?
他站在了历史错误的一边。
He was on the wrong side of history.
爸爸!
Papa!
[Jakub]我爸爸是个好人，但也做过坏事。
[Jakub] My dad was a good man who did bad things.
他是党的线人。
He was an informant for the Party.
你相信这个伟大的使命能弥补你父亲的罪过。
You believe this great mission will atone for the sins of your father.
你应该多关注那些瘦骨嶙峋的活人。
You should focus more on the living, skinny human.
现在该轮到你做父亲了。
It's your turn to be a father now.
[敲门]
[knock at door]
宝贝，有人来找你。
[softly] Baby, someone's here to see you.
[图玛]你想离开你丈夫?
[Tuma] You want to leave your husband?
我已经离开他了。
I have left him.
[图玛]不，你给他留了言。
[Tuma] No, you left him a message.
但问题是我还没给他。
But the thing is I haven't given it to him.
当然可以。
Of course.
我的工作是保护他。
My job is to protect him.
我是在保护他孩子的母亲。
I'm trying to protect the mother of his child.
你的任务很安全。
Your mission is safe.
我向你保证雅各布不会有事的。
I assure you Jakub will be fine.
他自己很好。
He's good on his own.
我敢肯定他很难相处。
I'm sure that he's hard to live with.
但是他做得不好。
But he's not doing well.
"他做得不好"是什么意思?
What does that mean, "he's not doing well"?
他想念他的妻子。
[Tuma] He misses his wife.
那他就不该走。
Then he shouldn't have left.
我不会给他留言的。
I'm not giving him your message.
(椅子擦伤)
[chair scrapes]
现在有人在你家里禁用CzechConnect。
[Tuma] There are people now at your home disabling the CzechConnect.
如果你不保护雅各布，那我来。
If you won't protect Jakub, I will.
现在，他需要相信
Right now, he needs to believe
你们俩仍然是一个爱情故事。
that the two of you are still a love story.
[Lenka]我不确定他知道。
[Lenka] I'm not sure he does.
当你丈夫身处危险境地时，你不会离开他的。
You don't leave your husband when he's in a dangerous place.
不是我让他去的。
I didn't put him there.
你为什么不能等他回来呢?
Why can't you wait until he comes back?
(深深地吸了口气)对不起。我帮不了你。
[inhales deeply] I'm sorry. I can't help you.
你知道吗，伦卡，保持沉默才是关键。
You know, Lenka, the silence is the point.
怎么啦？
What?
“我们都上了CzechConnect，但却一片沉默，
"We're both on CzechConnect and there is silence,
那有什么意义呢?”
so what is the point?"
沉默才是关键。
The silence is the point.
你们两个在一起
The two of you together,
沉默，迷失，恐惧，在黑暗中，
silent, lost, afraid, in the dark,
持有。
holding on.
这就是问题的关键。
That is the point.
[Jakub]速度为零。
[Jakub] Speed at zero.
[彼得]确认SSR。
[Peter] Confirm SSR.
[Jakub] SSR到达目标。旋转，12度。FSC订婚。
[Jakub] SSR on target. Rotation, 12 degrees. FSC engaged.
接触。完成了。
Contact. Done.
[Peter] FERDA收集模拟，场景Beta 3-3结束。
[Peter] FERDA Collection Simulation, Scenario Beta 3-3 concluded.
太好了,指挥官。这是完美的。
Great, Commander. That's perfect.
在这里待了六个月。我知道，彼得。
Six months in here. I know this, Peter.
[彼得]我知道，但还有45个小时呢。
[Peter] I know, but 45 hours to go.
你会先到的。
And you'll be there first.
我们为你感到骄傲。
We're very proud of you down here.
(Jakub)是的。
[Jakub] Yeah.
(Lenka)喂?
[Lenka] Hello?
从地球到Jakub?
Earth to Jakub?
你能停下来吗?我真的没有时间。
[Jakub] Will you stop? I really don't have time.
[哈努斯]这不是我造成的。
[Hanuš] I am not the cause of this.
[Lenka]你在吗?
[Lenka] Are you there?
(通过扬声器)对不起。
[Jakub over speakers] I'm sorry.
我只是又累又孤单。
I'm just tired and lonely.
[伦卡]我能理解。
[Lenka] I can relate.
[Jakub]我知道。
[Jakub] I know.
也许你可以跟我谈谈。
Maybe you could just talk to me.
[Jakub]你想谈什么?
[Jakub] What do you want to talk about?
[Lenka]。
[Lenka] Anything.
[哈努斯]这是什么?
[Hanuš] What is this?
你应该告诉我一个秘密。
You should tell me a secret.
[Jakub] Lenka，请接。
[Jakub] Lenka, please.
这是几个月前的老话题了。
This is an old conversation from months ago.
[Lenka]记得当你……
[Lenka] Remember when you…
终于告诉我你小时候发生了什么事了吗?
finally told me what happened to you when you were a boy?
[Jakub]怎么了?
[Jakub] What about it?
他们怎么因为你爸爸把你扔进河里?
[Lenka] How they threw you in the river because of your dad?
[Jakub]我还是不想谈论这件事。
[Jakub] And I still don't want to talk about it.
我只是想搞清楚你是谁，雅各布。
I'm just trying to make sense of who you are, Jakub.
[Jakub]这是怎么玩的?
[Jakub] How is this even playing?
你认定我是谁了?
[Jakub over speakers] Who have you decided I am?
我只知道你是一个说你想回家的人
All I know is that you're someone who says that you want to come home
然后说他们想看看木星之外是什么。
and then says they want to see what's beyond Jupiter.
我不能做梦吗?
[Jakub] Am I not allowed to dream?
他妈的!
Fuck!
当你做梦，你离开。
When you dream, you leave.
(Jakub)等等。
[Jakub] Whatever.
(开始震动)
[whirs]
[Jakub]哈努斯，那是
[Jakub] Hanuš, is that--
[哈努斯]一种来自起初的谷物!
[Hanuš] A grain from the Beginning!
Chopra !
It's Chopra!
(颤音)
[warbling]
(脉动)
[pulsating]
(颤音减少)
[warbling reduces]
难以置信!
Unbelievable!
是的!
Yes!
(喘着粗气)
[breathing heavily]
(颤音加剧)
[warbling intensifies]
哈努什:拿不住，瘦骨嶙峋的人。
[Hanuš] It cannot be held, skinny human.
不!不!
No! No!
[紧张的音乐播放]
[tense music playing]
(机器转动)
[machine whirring]
(很好的)
[rattling]
(巨大的)
[thumping]
[哈努斯]你让我的电视静音了。
[Hanuš] You have silenced my tube.
你那可耻的浪费不能满足你所寻求的。
Your shameful waste will not hold what you are looking for.
(Jakub普通员工)
[Jakub grunts]
(普通员工)
[grunts]
彼得，我觉得我们有麻烦了。
Peter, I think we have an issue here.
彼得?
Peter?
彼得，搞什么鬼?
Peter, what the fuck?
[不祥的音乐播放]
[ominous music playing]
控制,控制。你读书吗?
Control, Control. Do you read?
(点击)
[clicking]
[不祥的音乐继续]
[ominous music continues]
[Jakub]控制?
[Jakub] Control?
彼得，你读书吗?
Peter, do you read?
[不祥的音乐播放]
[ominous music playing]
哈努斯，你看到了吗?
Hanuš, do you see that?
[哈努斯]开端临近了。
[Hanuš] The Beginning approaches.
我应该担心吗?
Should I be concerned?
你没什么好怕的，瘦骨嶙峋的人类。
You have nothing to fear, skinny human.
开端不会造成任何伤害。
The Beginning will not cause any harm.
它仅仅是一个存储库。
It is merely a repository.
的什么?
Of what?
[哈努斯]你们部落的语言无法描述这一切。
[Hanuš] The words of your tribe cannot describe this.
也许我们会经历……
Perhaps we will experience it…
在一起。
together.
(小鸟喳喳叫)
[birds chirping]
[不祥的音乐播放]
[ominous music playing]
控制中心，收到吗?
Control, do you read?
[哈努斯]瘦削的人。
[Hanuš] Skinny human.
我必须问一件可能让你不高兴的事。
I must ask something that may upset you.
怎么啦？
What?
你的后代即将到来，
The upcoming arrival of your offspring,
为什么会让你的兰卡如此苦恼?
why should it cause your Lenka such distress?
它不是。
It doesn't.
[哈努斯]然而她的感觉是一种恐惧。
[Hanuš] Yet the flavor of her feelings is one of dread.
你们再次交配产生了这个后代。
You mated again to create this offspring.
你说起这个孩子时很兴奋。
You speak of this offspring with excitement.
我们经历过可怕的事情。
We've experienced things to fear.
[哈努斯]给我看看，瘦骨嶙峋的人。
[Hanuš] Show me, skinny human.
我不在场。
I wasn't there.
(呼呼)
[whirring]
[紧张的音乐播放]
[tense music playing]
哈努斯，我怎么能看出来?
Hanuš, how can I even see this?
-[Lenka呻吟]-[Jakub]我不在那里。
-[Lenka groaning] -[Jakub] I wasn't there.
[哈努斯]你的思想一直在那里，不是吗?
[Hanuš] Your thoughts have been there, haven't they?
(Lenka哭)
[Lenka crying]
[哈努斯]你向他描述过这个事件吗?
[Hanuš] You had the event described to you?
(歇斯底里地哭)
[crying hysterically]
我只想让你回家。
I just want you to come home.
但你知道我做不到。
But you know I can't do that.
[Lenka]我打赌你可以。
[Lenka] I bet you could.
[Jakub] Lenka, Cerný博士说什么?
[Jakub] Lenka, what is Dr. Cerný saying?
[哈努斯]当你的伴侣失去第一个孩子时，你不在。
[Hanuš] You were absent when your mate lost your first offspring.
从那以后你就缺席了。
You were absent thereafter.
那伤透了我的灵魂。
That broke my soul.
我只是觉得很孤单，雅各布。
I just feel so alone, Jakub.
[Jakub]哦，该死!狗屎!
[Jakub] Oh shit! Shit!
我有紧急情况。
I'm having an emergency.
我再打给你。
Let me call you back.
[伦卡]你去吧。
[Lenka] You do that.
CzechConnect让我们保持联系
CzechConnect keeps us connect--
她和你的孩子在一起，而你不在那里。
[Hanuš] Again, she is with your child, and you are not there.
对什么?
What for?
它带来的痛苦，对你有价值吗?
The pain that it causes, it is of value to you?
[忧郁的音乐播放]
[melancholy music playing]
[女]你能和我们在一起是我们的荣幸。
[woman] It's an honor to have you with us.
[Lenka]我确信我在这里
[Lenka] I'm sure my being here
和其他人没什么不同，但是谢谢你。
is no different to anybody else, but thank you.
嗯。当然，但我们对所有的顾客都这么说，我们是认真的。
Hm. Of course, but we say this to all our patrons, and we mean it.
我们对自己的任务很谦虚。
We are humble to our task.
无论是出于选择还是不得已，
Whether it's by choice or by necessity,
这不是一件容易的事。
this is not an easy thing to carry on your own.
Útočiště是你的避难所或腹地，
Útočiště is your sanctuary or hinterland,
你想要什么都行。
whatever you need it to be.
[Lenka]谢谢。
[Lenka] Thank you.
(呼呼)
[whirring]
[紧张的音乐播放]
[tense music plays]
[哈努斯]根据我们所有的发现，
[Hanuš] With all our findings,
你仍然专注于你的伟大发现。
you are still focused on your great discovery.
[Jakub]我正在想办法联系到任务控制中心。
[Jakub] I'm focused on a way to reach Mission Control.
[哈努斯]我们还没有结束。
[Hanuš] We're not done.
你至少为我感到高兴吧?
[Jakub] Are you at least happy for me?
是的。
Yeah.
我当然是。(抽泣)
Of course I am. [sniffles]
我为你感到高兴和骄傲。(抽泣)
I'm happy and proud of you. [sniffles]
他们选择了你。
They chose you.
[Jakub]我们会成功的。
[Jakub] We'll make it work.
-我们在一起。你和我。——(Lenka抽泣)
-We're together in this. You and me. -[Lenka sniffles]
答应我一件事。
[Lenka] Promise me one thing.
答应我，我们还会按照之前说好的去做。
Promise me we're still going to do all the things we talked about.
[Jakub]当然。我保证。
[Jakub] Of course. I promise.
她感觉到你的谎言在她心里。
[Hanuš] She feels your lies inside her.
你不知道你在说什么。
[Jakub] You don't know what you're talking about.
你欢迎她的悲伤。
[Hanuš] You welcomed her sadness.
所有这些破碎的誓言
All these broken pledges
除了你的伟大发现。
except for the one you made to your great discovery.
你怎么会看不见呢
How could you fail to see
有一天，她会失去对你的信任?
that she, one day, would lose the will to believe in you?
(键盘哔哔声)
[keypad beeping]
(线响)
[line ringing]
加油，加油，加油。
Come on, come on, come on.
[彼得]我是彼得。
[Peter] This is Peter.
彼得，我是雅各布。我是CzechConnect的。
Peter, it's Jakub. I'm calling from the CzechConnect.
我找到了重新配置它的方法。
I found a way to reconfigure it.
无线电坏了，但这个好像有用。
The radio's down, but this seems to work.
我不知道你能不能听到。彼得?
I don't know if you can hear me. Peter?
(彼得紧张地笑)我们以为我们失去了联系。
[Peter chuckles nervously] We thought we lost communication.
自从你消失后，这里的每个人都在执勤。
Everyone here has been on comms duty since you went dark.
你黑了CzechConnect?这是难以置信的。
And you hacked the CzechConnect? That's unbelievable.
是的。
Yeah.
你还好吗?船还好吗?
Are you okay? Is the ship okay?
是的，一切都是
Yes, everything is--
(静态)
[static]
哈努什:我还想看更多的东西。
[Hanuš] There is more I want to see.
请不要总是说一切都会好起来的。
[Lenka] Please don't keep saying everything will be fine.
[Jakub]但它会的。
[Jakub] But it will.
你想得太多了。
You think too much.
我知道已经一年了，但我们知道该怎么做。
I know it's a year, but we know how to do this.
[Lenka]当你一个人的时候，事情总会发生。
[Lenka] Things happen when you're alone.
[Jakub]我们会熬过去的。
[Jakub] We'll get through it.
这是最后一次。
This is the last time.
[Lenka]你也一直这么说。
[Lenka] You keep saying that too.
你害怕吗?
Are you frightened?
[Jakub]我告诉过你没什么好怕的。
[Jakub] I told you there's nothing to be afraid of.
[Lenka]你就没想过成本吗?
[Lenka] Don't you ever think about the cost?
我们为这一切付出的代价?
The price we have to pay for it all?
你和我。
You and me.
我很担心你。我不知道前方会发生什么。
I'm worried. I don't know what lies ahead.
你为什么不呢?
Why aren't you?
[哈努斯]我深信，
[Hanuš] With great conviction,
你甚至没有试着去理解你的伴侣。
you do not even try to understand your mate.
目的是什么?
To what end?
与人沟通是不可能的
It is impossible to connect with someone
除了他自己什么都不想看到，
who does not want to see anything but himself,
他只在对自己有利的时候才想要联系。
who only wants to connect when it serves him.
一开始，我以为这是你们的本性，
At first, I thought it was your kind's nature,
自私,短视。
selfishness, shortsightedness.
但通过你的蓝卡，我看到了。
But through your Lenka, I now see it.
是你。
It is you.
你的孤独是自己造成的。
Your loneliness is self-inflicted.
我就不打扰你了。
I will leave you to your mission.
怎么啦？Hanuš!
What? Hanuš!
我对你的兴趣已经过期了。
[Hanuš] My interest in you has expired.
你不能离开我。
[Jakub] You can't leave me.
我需要你。
I need you.
你帮助!我在听你说!
You're helping! I'm listening to you!
[哈努斯]你没办法。
[Hanuš] You can't be helped.
不!
No!
(砰砰声)
[thuds]
我希望你不要把手放在我身上。
[Hanuš] I prefer you do not place your hands on me.
(紧张)
[straining]
(喘气)
[panting]
你不能走。
You can't leave.
我需要——
I need to--
[哈努斯]你需要带着一个非常不同的发现回来，
[Hanuš] You need to come back with a very different discovery,
但你只能看到你自己。
but all you can see is yourself.
祝你好运，瘦骨嶙峋的人。
Good luck, skinny human.
Hanuš。
Hanuš.
不!等等!
No! Wait!
Hanuš吗?
Hanuš?
请Hanuš。
Hanuš, please.
我愿意做任何事。
I'll do anything.
请Hanuš。我保证。
Hanuš, please. I promise.
[迷人的音乐播放]
[captivating music playing]
[Jakub]这是什么?
[Jakub] What is this?
这是一个秘密的地方。
It's a secret place.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
我想住在这里。
I think I want to live here.
[Lenka]也许你想一起去执行任务。
[Lenka] Maybe you'd like to go on a mission together.
也许你想和我交换秘密。
Maybe you'd like to trade secrets.
也许你想吻我。
Maybe you'd like to kiss me.
我会的。
I would.
好了。
Nice.
[]音乐逐渐变强
[music crescendos]
(轻声哭泣)
[cries softly]
(音乐消失)
[music fades]
(电话响了)
[phone ringing]
[Jakub]彼得!
[Jakub] Peter!
搞什么鬼?你去哪儿了?
What the hell? Where did you go?
我相信你能想象，这里有各种各样的原因造成了严重的恐慌。
There is a severe panic down here for all reasons I'm sure you can imagine.
彼得，一切都好。
Peter, everything is okay.
一切都没有偏离计划。
Nothing is deviating from plan.
这艘船在做它设计的任务。
The ship is doing what it was designed to do.
当通信中断或通信中断时，有一个行动方案，
There's a course of action for when or if communications break down,
我正在按照每一个排练过的步骤
and I am following each of those rehearsed steps,
包括解决这个问题。
including fixing that problem.
你他妈的冷静点。
Calm the fuck down.
给我提个醒。
Give me a heads-up.
在此之前，我要你先去看看兰卡。
Before anything, I want you to go and see Lenka.
怎么啦？为什么?
What? Why?
现在我们有很多事要做。
Right now we have a lot going on.
彼得。-韩国人就在你后面。
-Peter. -The South Koreans are right behind you.
你得走了。
You are gonna go.
[彼得]做什么?
[Peter] To do what?
[深深地呼吸]
[all breathing deeply]
Lenka Prochazka吗?
Lenka Procházka?
哦，他还活着。
Oh, he's alive.
妈的，彼得!
For fuck's sake, Peter!
[松了口气]
[sighs in relief]
我得跟你谈谈，兰卡。请给我五分钟。
I need to talk to you, Lenka. Five minutes, please.
我不是来干涉的。
I'm not here to interfere.
不管发生了什么，那是你们俩之间的事。
Whatever is going on, that's between the two of you.
但为了这次任务的安全考虑，
But in the interest of the safety of the mission and the stakes,
我现在要尽我所能减轻雅各布的精神状态。
I need to do what I can to alleviate Jakub's mental state right now.
我希望你能理解。
I hope you can understand that.
彼得……
Peter…
我不能。
I can't.
他想让你听。这是所有。
He wants you to listen. That's all.
[彼得深吸一口气]
[Peter breathes deeply]
[电话键盘哔哔声]
[phone keypad beeping]
(彼得低声说)我在外面。
[Peter whispers] I'll be outside.
[Jakub] Lenka，我希望你在那里。
[Jakub] Lenka, I hope you're there.
我现在明白了。我做的事。
I get it now. I do.
你还记得我说过我想看看木星以外的地方吗?
Do you remember when I said I wanted to see beyond Jupiter?
我想不出还有什么比这更糟的了。
I can't imagine anything worse now.
我只想回家。
I just want to come home.
当我们相遇时，我有生以来第一次感到安全。
When we met, I felt safe for the first time in my life.
现在我怎么也弄不明白，为什么我一直把你抛在身后
And now I can't, for the life of me, understand why I kept leaving you behind
当你是我唯一在乎的时候。
when you're the only thing that matters.
你努力去了解我。
You tried hard to know me.
我很抱歉我从来没有真正努力去了解你。
I am so sorry I never made a real effort to know you.
你就在我面前，我却没看见你。
You were right there in front of me, and I didn't see you.
我的一生都是为了错误的理由而活。
I have lived a life for all the wrong reasons.
真是他妈的浪费。
What a fucking waste.
我配不上你。
I don't deserve you.
-我从来没有。——(叹息)
-And I never have. -[sighs]
[Jakub]如果我能再来一次，我会做得更好。
[Jakub] If I could do it again, I'd do it better.
(Lenka抽泣)
[Lenka sniffles]
[雅库布]我永远不会违背这个承诺。
[Jakub] And that's a promise I would never ever break.
如果我…如果我能再来一次。
If I… If I could do it again.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
[忧郁的音乐播放]
[melancholy music playing]
(哭)
[crying]
[忧郁的音乐继续]
[melancholy music continues]
(音乐消失)
[music fades]
[Jakub] Hanuš吗?
[Jakub] Hanuš?
我能感觉到你在到处乱摸。
I can feel you poking around.
你还在这儿吗?
Are you still here?
哈努斯:你现在应该休息了。
[Hanuš] You should rest now.
我，我真的很乐意。
I-- I'd really like that.
[Hanuš)休息。
[Hanuš] Rest.
你被净化了，瘦弱的人类。
You have purged, skinny human.
我看到了。
I saw it.
休息。
Rest.
[哈努斯喘着粗气]
[Hanuš breathing heavily]
我不是故意吵醒你的。
I did not mean to wake you.
别再那样对我了。
Don't do that to me again.
别离开我。
Don't leave me.
我不能让你独自面对起点。
[Hanuš] I cannot let you face the Beginning alone.
我开始明白，我也不想一个人呆着。
I've come to understand that I don't want to be alone for that either.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
[Hanuš喘息)
[Hanuš wheezing]
你怎么了?
Wha-- What's happening to you?
(哈努什颤抖地吸了口气)我之前没有对你完全诚实。
[Hanuš inhales shakily] I was not entirely honest with you before.
关于什么?
About what?
我跟你说了哥罗柏人来找我们了。
I told you the Gorompeds came for us.
他们吞噬了我们的后代，我们的长辈。
They consumed our offspring, our elders.
所以我逃离了我的世界。
So I fled my world.
但我逃得太晚了。
But I fled too late.
你吓到我了。
You're scaring me.
[哈努斯]为什么害怕真相?
[Hanuš] Why fear a truth?
这不是我的方式，
This is not the way of my kind,
但这就是人类的生活方式。
but it is the way of humans.
我开始明白为什么白日梦和噩梦，
I'm starting to understand why daydreams and nightmares,
它们都是本质上的。
they are both of essence.
你怎么什么都不说?
[Jakub] Why didn't you say anything?
你从来没问过我。
You never asked about me.
[Hanuš喘息)
[Hanuš wheezing]
[Jakub]请找哈努斯。
[Jakub] Hanuš, please.
你该休息了，瘦子。
You should rest, skinny human.
明天，我们将进入开端。
Tomorrow, we enter the Beginning.
(蟋蟀鸣叫)
[crickets chirping]
这一切感觉就像我们给孩子们讲的一个不真实的梦幻故事。
This all feels like an unreal, dreamy story we tell the kids.
“你出生那年，天空是紫色的。”
"The year you were born the sky was purple."
“没人知道原因。”
"No one knew why."
他们认为这是来自外太空的粒子。
They think it's particles from deep space.
你能想象在上面的情景吗?
[woman] Can you imagine being up there?
没有重力。你可以漂走。
No gravity. You can float away.
[Lenka]这就是我在这里的感觉。
[Lenka] That's how I feel here sometimes.
我宁愿待在这里也不愿追逐太空尘埃。
I'd rather be here than chasing space dust.
这是一种非常闪亮的灰尘。(温柔的笑)
It's a very glittery dust. [chuckles softly]
[迷人的音乐播放]
[captivating music playing]
[哈努什颤抖地呼吸]
[Hanuš breathing shakily]
瘦弱的人，是时候了。
Skinny human, it is time.
等待着你伟大的发现。
Your great discovery awaits.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
[哈努斯]热豆水，是一种神圣的仪式。
[Hanuš] The hot bean water, it is a sacred ritual.
[Jakub]有家的味道。
[Jakub] Tastes like home.
[播放悬疑音乐]
[suspenseful music playing]
测试，测试，测试!
Test, test, test!
[彼得]是的，我还在读你的书。
[Peter] Yeah, still reading you.
指挥官，我要告诉你
Commander, I need to tell you
我们开始播放你最新的预录。
we initiated the broadcast of your latest pre-recording.
我们都知道这对你来说是一个重要的时刻在现场，在现场。
We all know it was an important moment for you to do that live, in person.
摄像机坏了，我们别无选择。
We had no choice with the cameras down.
你演得很好。
You're really good in it.
没关系，彼得。
It's okay, Peter.
[图马]指挥官Procházka，
[Tuma] Commander Procházka,
感谢您在这些宝贵的时刻抽出时间。
thank you for taking the time in these precious moments.
你感觉怎么样?
How are you feeling?
[Jakub]图马局长，我感到谦卑、敬畏，同时也很专注。
[Jakub] Commissioner Tuma, I am humbled, awed, and focused all in one breath.
想想一个在农村长大的孩子
To think a kid growing up in the countryside
总有一天会参与其中。
would one day partake in this.
过一会儿，我们将把FERDA部署到乔普拉，
In just a few moments, we will deploy FERDA into Chopra,
但在那之前，
but before that,
我只想说，我非常感谢捷克人民对我的支持。
I just have to say how grateful I am for the support of the Czech people.
这一使命是献给全世界人民的
This mission is dedicated to the people of the world
而资助者和赞助者，
and the funders and sponsors,
当然还有伦卡。
and to Lenka, of course.
感谢她无尽的支持。
For her endless support.
两个恋人隔着星星相连。
[Tuma] Two lovers connected across the stars.
我相信她很期待你平安归来。
I'm sure she's looking forward to having you home, safe and sound.
地球上的每个人都在看。
Everyone here on Earth is watching.
因为再过几分钟，
Because in just a few minutes,
Jan Hus 1和Commander Procházka
the Jan Hus 1 and Commander Procházka
将进入乔普拉云。
will be entering the Chopra Cloud.
捷克自豪地击败了韩国队
The Czech Republic has proudly beaten the South Korean mission
成为第一个调查紫色幽灵的人
to be the first to investigate the purple specter
它在过去的四年里一直困扰着我们的天空。
that has haunted our sky for these past four years.
[Jakub]自动调节液压系统。
[Jakub] Arming hydraulics.
(机械增长)
[mechanical humming]
绿色板。
Green board.
(哈努斯小声说)我们正站在通往宇宙的门口。
[Hanuš whispers] We are on the doorstep to the universe.
准备好了吗，瘦骨嶙峋的人?
You are ready, skinny human?
是的。是的，我是。
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
[彼得]这里是绿板，雅各布。
[Peter] Green board here, Jakub.
倒数第T - 10秒。
Count yourself to sample collection in T minus ten.
[Jakub]速度为零。
[Jakub] Speed zero.
[彼得，扭曲]20岁以下的SSR。
[Peter, distorted] SSR under 20.
[Jakub] SSR在20。
[Jakub] SSR at 20.
释放盖茨。
Releasing gates.
[播放悬疑音乐]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Jakub]武器开火了。
[Jakub] Arm engaged.
旋转，8度。
Rotation, eight degrees.
FERDA正在部署收集。
FERDA is deploying for collection.
但这可能是毫无意义的努力。
But it might be a pointless endeavor.
(彼得，声音扭曲)我们听不到你说什么，雅各布。我们的…[静电]…不规则。
[Peter, distorted] We can't hear you, Jakub. Our… [static] …irregularities.
控制中心，我们受到干扰。
Control, we're getting some interference.
[彼得]我们读到…我们现在读到你了。
[Peter] We read… We read you now.
[扭曲]清除样本收集。
[distorted] Clear for the sample collection.
[Jakub] FSC交战。
[Jakub] FSC engaged.
接触。
Contact.
尝试收集。
Attempting collection.
[哈努斯]瘦削的人。
[Hanuš] Skinny human.
(哮喘)
[wheezing]
我从来没有听到过这样的沉默。
I've never heard such silence before.
-[咕噜声]-[颤音，搏动]
-[grunts] -[warbling, pulsating]
-[警报声]-[哈努什的咕噜声]
-[alarm blaring] -[Hanuš grunting]
Hanuš!
[彼得]指挥官，怎么回事?
[Peter] Commander, what is happening?
-我们有负面读数…-哈努斯!
-[Peter] We have negative reading… -Hanuš!
从样品收集中。
…from sample collection.
-有点不对劲。-Hanuš!
-Something is wrong. -Hanuš!
[Peter] FERDA系统故障。
[Peter] System failure from FERDA.
立即中止样品收集。
Abort sample collection immediately.
Hanuš!
我们记录到大量的故障，指挥官。
[Peter] We are recording numerous malfunctions, Commander.
你必须马上退出。
You have to pull out immediately.
取消任务!
Abort the mission!
[在CzechConnect上的扭曲喋喋不休]
[distorted chatter over CzechConnect]
[彼得]你有灾难性的系统故障。
[Peter] You have catastrophic system failure.
雅库布，我们听不见。
Jakub, we cannot hear you.
这些指标显示出了不正常的现象。
The indicators are showing irregularities.
[哈努斯]别害怕，瘦骨嶙峋的人。
[Hanuš] Fear not, skinny human.
[Jakub] Hanuš!坚持住!我来了!
[Jakub] Hanuš! Hold on! I'm coming!
[彼得]中止样本收集
[Peter] Abort the sample collection
并启动推进器。-不!不，我不能。
-and engage thrusters. -No! No, I can't.
[彼得]你拿炸弹干什么?
[Peter] What are you doing with the Bomba?
指挥官，马上撤退!请重复一遍!
Commander, pull out now! Please repeat!
[紧张的音乐播放]
[tense music playing]
[彼得]指挥官，怎么回事?
[Peter] Commander, what is happening?
(闹钟刺耳)
[alarm blaring]
[彼得]你为什么在气闸里?
[Peter] Why are you in the airlock?
宇航服传感器启动。
Suit sensors are engaged.
彼得，我要出去!
Peter, I'm going out!
你他妈的疯了吗?
Are you fucking crazy?
忘了乔普拉吧，指挥官。
Forget Chopra, Commander.
退出!拯救你自己!
Pull out! Save yourself!
[Jakub]我有件事要做!我马上回来!
[Jakub] There's something I've gotta do! I'll be right back!
指挥官，我们听不到你说话!
[Peter] Commander, we can't read you!
请进，指挥官!
Come in, Commander!
(气闸发声)
[airlock hissing]
[Jakub]加油，加油，加油!
[Jakub] Come on, come on, come on!
[紧张的音乐继续]
[tense music continues]
[Jakub] Hanuš!
(喘气)
[panting]
(普通员工)
[grunts]
(喘气)
[panting]
[Jakub] Hanuš!
你还好吗?炸弹奏效了吗?
Are you okay? Did the Bomba work?
瘦骨嶙骨的人类，你清除污染物的努力是英勇的。
[Hanuš] Skinny human, your efforts with the decontaminant were heroic.
但很快，哥罗盘人就会削弱我的力量，吃掉我的肉。
But soon, the Gorompeds will weaken me enough to consume my flesh.
但我们还有一点时间。
But we have a little time.
死神还找不到我
Death will not yet find me.
[忧郁的音乐播放]
[melancholy music playing]
[Jakub喘着粗气]
[Jakub breathing heavily]
[Jakub] Hanuš。
[Jakub] Hanuš.
我小时候差点淹死。
I almost drowned when I was a boy.
这让我想起了那件事。
This reminds me of that.
我可以透过水看到太阳，绿色的，闪烁着。
I could see the sun through the water, green and flickering.
我知道我快要淹死了
I knew then I was drowning,
但太阳会继续照耀。
but the sun would go on shining.
哦,爸爸。我赦免你的罪，
Oh, Dad. I absolve you of your sins,
我也赦免我自己。
and I absolve me of them too.
[Hanuš]漂亮。
[Hanuš] Beautiful.
在这里结束一切还不错。
This isn't such a bad place to end things.
[哈努斯]这还不是结束。
[Hanuš] This isn't the end.
来了。让我示范给你看。
Come. Let me show you.
[迷人的音乐播放]
[captivating music playing]
[女孩模糊地唱歌]
[girl singing indistinctly]
[Jakub]我们才刚认识，不过我觉得还可以。
[Jakub] We only just met but I'd be okay with it.
(婴儿哭)
[baby crying]
[车辆喇叭声]
[vehicle horn blares]
这就是我不说真话的原因。
[Jakub] This is why I don't tell the truth.
这是什么?
What is this?
[哈努斯]瘦骨嶙峋的人，就是这样。
[Hanuš] Skinny human, this is it.
这就是一切。
This is everything.
这是开始也是结束。
This is the Beginning and the ending.
(孩子笑)
[child laughs]
[哈努斯]所有时间的每一个振动。
[Hanuš] Every vibration of all time.
都包含在这里。
It is all contained here.
彼得:太好了，指挥官。这是完美的。
[Peter] Great, Commander. That's perfect.
你的过去和未来。
[Hanuš] Your past and your future.
(男孩)嘿!等等我!
[boy] Hey! Wait for me!
我，你，你的Lenka……
[Hanuš] Me, you, your Lenka…
我去哪里你就去哪里，你去哪里我就去哪里。宇航员?
[Lenka] You go where I go, and I go where you go. Right, Spaceman?
[哈努斯]你父亲。
[Hanuš] Your father.
[人]Jakub !
[man] Jakub!
[哈努斯]每一个承诺。每一个心碎。
[Hanuš] Every promise. Every heartbreak.
[Lenka]地球到Jakub?
[Lenka] Earth to Jakub?
[哈努斯]每一次赎罪。
[Hanuš] Every atonement.
我来了!
[boy] I'm coming!
一切都是永恒的，但没有什么是永恒的。
[Hanuš] Everything is permanent, yet nothing ever is.
(Jakub)真的吗?这是小?
[Jakub] Really? It's tiny?
这就是宇宙的真理。
That is the truth of the universe.
(颤音)
[warbling]
[Lenka]你有没有想过
[Lenka] You ever think about
你在晚年学到了什么?
what you've learned a little bit late in life?
[Jakub]也许我还没到那个地步。
[Jakub] Maybe I'm not at that point yet.
[哈努斯]没人会受伤
[Hanuš] No one has to hurt,
不是在这里，你什么都能看到。
not here where you can see everything.
(烟花爆炸)
[fireworks bursting]
(呻吟)
[groaning]
(尖叫)
[screaming]
(心跳怦怦地跳)
[heartbeat thumping]
(婴儿哭)
[baby crying]
[播放歌剧音乐]
[operatic music playing]
(喘气)
[panting]
Hanuš!难以置信!
Hanuš! Incredible!
[哈努斯]瘦弱的人类，宇宙就是它应该有的样子。
[Hanuš] Skinny human, the universe is as it should be.
[Jakub]是的。
[Jakub] Yes, it is.
我所知甚少。
How little I knew.
但有一件事我一直都很清楚。
But there's one thing I've always known.
来，我指给你看。
Come, let me show you.
[哈努斯]这是开始。
[Hanuš] This is the Beginning.
用你的蓝卡。
With your Lenka.
你没事吧，太空人?
You all right there, Spaceman?
[Jakub]我第一次见到她，就知道我希望她过得好。
[Jakub] The first moment I saw her, I knew I wanted good things for her.
就算我什么都不知道，我也知道。
If I don't know anything else, I know that.
要是我一直像那时那样看她就好了。
If only I saw her always like I saw her then.
[哈努斯]你能见到她已经是个奇迹了。
[Hanuš] That you saw her at all is a miracle.
[Jakub]我和她不太可能见面，
[Jakub] It's all so unlikely that she and I would meet,
你和我会见面
that you and I would meet.
[哈努斯]然而我们在这里。
[Hanuš] Yet here we are.
你以为这就是你想要的一切，
You thought this was everything you wanted,
这里没有什么，雅各布?
so what's not here, Jakub?
[Jakub]她不在这里。
[Jakub] She's not here.
时间到了，不是吗?
It's time, isn't it?
我感觉你在悄悄溜走。
I feel you slipping away.
[哈努斯]是的，这是不可避免的。
[Hanuš] Yes, it is inevitable.
这并非没有恐惧，
It's not without some fear,
但我现在可以离开你了。
but I can leave you now.
我给你带了点东西。
[Jakub] I brought something for you.
舒缓的。
For soothing.
[哈努斯]谢谢。
[Hanuš] Thank you.
我在这里开始，也在这里结束。
I begin and I end here.
(哈努什喘着气)但也许这不是你的结局，瘦小的人类。
[Hanuš gasps] But perhaps this is not your ending, skinny human.
现在我感到恐惧。
Now I feel fear.
[哈努斯]跟你一样。
[Hanuš] As you do.
但你也对自己抱有希望，你的兰卡。
But you also feel hope for you, your Lenka.
这就是你们部落的智慧。
That is the wisdom of your tribe.
你能听到她说话吗?
Can you hear her?
[Jakub]我什么都听不见。
[Jakub] I can't hear anything.
[哈努斯]倾听寂静。
[Hanuš] Listen to the silence.
谢谢你，哈努斯。为我所做的一切。
Thank you, Hanuš. For everything.
[哈努斯]有家的味道。
[Hanuš] Tastes like home.
[播放忧郁的音乐]
[somber music playing]
[Jakub喘息声)
[Jakub gasps]
不。
No.
不!
No!
不，不，不，不。
No, no, no, no, no, no.
哦,Hanuš。
Oh, Hanuš.
[忧郁的音乐继续]
[somber music continues]
[Jakub]水泽仙女……
[Jakub] Rusalka…
我只想要一个吻。
I just want a kiss.
你知道那会害死你的。
You know that will kill you.
(轻声地)我对此很满意。
[softly] I'm good with that.
Lenka。
Lenka.
Jakub。
Jakub.
[模糊的无线电杂音]
[indistinct radio chatter]
(电话响了)
[phone ringing]
[女人在电话里说韩语]
[woman speaks Korean over phone]
[Jakub]谢谢。
[Jakub] Thank you.
如果我当时知道我现在知道的，
If I had known then what I know now,
我永远不会离开。
I never would have left.
如果我当时知道我现在知道的，
If I had known then what I know now,
我会吻你吗?
would I have kissed you?
你会吗?
Would you?
你会再吻我一次吗?
Would you kiss me again?
那真是一个美妙的吻。
It was a really good kiss.
[播放《别走》]
["Don't Go Away" playing]
♬别走，别走，别走
♪ Don't go away, don't go away Don't go away, don't go away ♪
♬别走开
♪ Don't go away ♪
♬请不要走
♪ Please don't go ♪
♬我会孤身一人
♪ I'd be all alone ♪
♬我需要你♬
♪ I need you ♪
♬请不要走
♪ Please don't go ♪
♬我会孤身一人
♪ I'd be all alone ♪
♬我需要你♬
♪ I need you ♪
♬别走，别走，别走
♪ Don't go away, don't go away Don't go away, don't go away ♪
♬别走开
♪ Don't go away ♪
♬别走，别走，别走
♪ Don't go away, don't go away Don't go away, don't go away ♪
♬别走开
♪ Don't go away ♪
♬你似乎很了解我
♪ You seem to know me ♪
♬比我更了解我自己
♪ Better than I know me ♪
♬比我更了解自己♬
♪ Better than I know myself ♪
♬你似乎很了解我
♪ You seem to know me ♪
♬比我更了解我自己
♪ Better than I know me ♪
♬比我更了解自己♬
♪ Better than I know myself ♪
♬别走，别走，别走
♪ Don't go away, don't go away Don't go away, don't go away ♪
♬别走开
♪ Don't go away ♪
♬别走，别走，别走
♪ Don't go away, don't go away Don't go away, don't go away ♪
♬别走开
♪ Don't go away ♪
♬请不要走
♪ Please don't go ♪
♬我会孤身一人
♪ I'd be all alone ♪
♬我需要你♬
♪ I need you ♪
♬请不要走
♪ Please don't go ♪
♬我会孤身一人
♪ I'd be all alone ♪
♬我需要你♬
♪ I need you ♪
♬别走，别走，别走
♪ Don't go away, don't go away Don't go away, don't go away ♪
♬别走开
♪ Don't go away ♪
♬别走，别走，别走
♪ Don't go away, don't go away Don't go away, don't go away ♪
♬别走开
♪ Don't go away ♪
♬漆黑的天空
♪ Deep, dark skies ♪
♬在太阳不升起的地方
♪ Where the sun don't rise ♪
♬我需要你♬
♪ I need you ♪
如果你离开
♪ If you leave ♪
♬你会危及♬
♪ You will jeopardize ♪
♬希望给我
♪ Hope for me ♪
♬希望属于你
♪ Hope for you ♪
♬别走，别走，别走
♪ Don't go away, don't go away Don't go away, don't go away ♪
♬别走开
♪ Don't go away ♪
♬别走，别走，别走
♪ Don't go away, don't go away Don't go away, don't go away ♪
♬别走开
♪ Don't go away ♪
♬你似乎很了解我
♪ You seem to know me ♪
♬比我更了解我自己
♪ Better than I know me ♪
♬比我更了解自己♬
♪ Better than I know myself ♪
♬你似乎很了解我
♪ You seem to know me ♪
♬比我更了解我自己
♪ Better than I know me ♪
♬比我更了解自己♬
♪ Better than I know myself ♪
♬别走，别走，别走
♪ Don't go away, don't go away Don't go away, don't go away ♪
♬别走开
♪ Don't go away ♪
♬别走，别走，别走
♪ Don't go away, don't go away Don't go away, don't go away ♪
♬别走开
♪ Don't go away ♪
♬你似乎很了解我
♪ You seem to know me ♪
♬比我更了解我自己
♪ Better than I know me ♪
♬比我更了解自己♬
♪ Better than I know myself ♪
♬你似乎很了解我
♪ You seem to know me ♪
♬比我更了解我自己
♪ Better than I know me ♪
♬比我更了解自己♬
♪ Better than I know myself ♪
[歌曲结束]我知道自己♬
[song ends] han I know myself ♪